Hello and welcome to the non-volatile storage implementation section in this section, I'll give a brief
overview of the SPF in vs library and how we're going to use it to save and load wi fi credentials.
So first, let's take a look at the implementation.
After the SB 32 successfully connects to an access point via the Web page, the SSA, ID and password
used to connect will be saved to flesh and upon startup.
The SB 32 will check the flash for any saved credentials and if there are any, they will be used to
attempt to connection immediately.
This is a very common set up in DeFi applications.
Also upon startup.
If after the Max connection retrace is reached and a connection attempt cannot be established.
We will clear the flash so those credentials won't be used to connect anymore.
If the disconnect button on the Web page is used to disconnect, the credentials will also be cleared
from the flesh in this case as well.
And once you have an idea of setting up the state machine and the Wi-Fi application so that these actions
can be handled, you'll be able to customize or adjust the application to your needs.
All right, so let's take a look at some of the APIs from the impressive body of inverse library and
how we can use them.
All right, so here is a link to impressive documentation for the non-volatile storage library and API
reference.
I do suggest you do some reading on your own here and at least browse over the introduction underlying
storage keys and values in namespace sections.
You can also find examples and information about other features that we will not use in this course.
In general, NCVHS components save and load data from storage that is preserved between boots so you
can turn the device off or if it loses power.
The data that you've stored will still be there for retrieval when it starts up again.
In the documentation, it's noted that invest using the impressive development framework works best
for storing small values e.g. Wi-Fi credentials in our case.
And about keys and values, envious operates on the key value pairs, keys or ASCII strings and values
are the types, for example, integer types, strings and variable length byte binary data, also known
as blobs.
And about namespaces, we assign each key value pair to a namespace, and we specify this namespace
when using certain inverse APIs, for example, and vice open.
OK, so let's take a look at some more specifics regarding saving and retrieving white flight credentials
to begin with saving credentials.
We need to open the storage area with the given name space.
We'll call PNB's open and specify the name space name.
Open in read write mode in our case and pass the handle to be used for subsequent calls to end via set
and invest commit functions to set the SSA, ID and password and for the Navy open function.
The first parameter taken is the name space, then the mode which is envious, read, write or invest,
read only and the third parameter is the handle.
And if successful, the return code is zero.
We will then set the variable length binary value for the society and password using Nvidia's set blub,
which takes the handle obtained from the envious open function.
Note we cannot use the set function if the handle was opened and read only mode.
All right, so then the key name, for example, we'll say suicide in quotation marks, then the next
parameter is the actual value to set, which is the suicide ID and password, and then we'll specify
the length.
After setting the values, we need to write the changes to non-volatile storage using NCVHS commit,
which takes the handle as the only parameter and for getting the credentials on startup, will also
need to call and be as open.
And then in our case, we'll call invoice get blub, which takes the handle the key name that we had
previously used when saving and the value which will have to dynamically allocate memory for and the
size or length as well.
When we need to clear the credentials, will again open the storage area using NGV's open in read write
mode, then we'll erase the key value pairs using envy as a result, which only takes the handle and
after racing, will commit the changes to NPS using NCVHS commit.
So that's all we need to cover for now.
Let's get decoding.